<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Tryton Van Meer</title>
    <link>https://trytonvanmeer.dev/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Tryton Van Meer</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 30 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://trytonvanmeer.dev/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Porting Hiritsu to Rust</title>
      <link>https://trytonvanmeer.dev/posts/hiritsu-rust-port/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trytonvanmeer.dev/posts/hiritsu-rust-port/</guid>
      <description>Hiritsu is a tool I developed to get the resolution and aspect ratio of images. It can also be used to rename an input image to include those attributes in the filename.
An example of this in action:
$ hiritsu wallpaper.jpg Width: 1920 Height: 1080 Ratio: 16:9 $ hiritsu --rename wallpaper.jpg wallpaper (1920x1080) [16:9].jpg The Python version can be found here, and the Rust port here
Benchmarking For this benchmark I used this wallpaper from Wallhaven.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Surface Pro 3 on Arch Linux with GNOME</title>
      <link>https://trytonvanmeer.dev/posts/2020-03-30-sp3-archlinux-gnome/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trytonvanmeer.dev/posts/2020-03-30-sp3-archlinux-gnome/</guid>
      <description>Recently, I acquired a Surface Pro 3 for a great deal. I was looking for a small computing device and wanted something I could run desktop Linux on, so an Android tablet or Chromebook were out of the race already.
I settled on the SP3 for a couple reasons:
 It has x86 hardware so no issues installing Linux. The SP3, while quite old at this point (released in 2014), has out of the box Linux support.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fish is Awesome! And tweaking the DNF completion.</title>
      <link>https://trytonvanmeer.dev/posts/2020-03-28-fish-is-great-dnf-completion/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trytonvanmeer.dev/posts/2020-03-28-fish-is-great-dnf-completion/</guid>
      <description>A while ago I decided to finally switched to ZSH and give it a try. Got it mostly configured to how I wanted it and was satisfied.
Then a friend mentioned he uses Fish. Well, I&amp;rsquo;m already trying an alternative shell, so why not give Fish a go.
Fish. Is. Awesome.
I&amp;rsquo;ve heard about how great Fish and ZSH were but always stuck to just using Bash. I was now thinking to myself, why didn&amp;rsquo;t I try these earlier.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Yes, I am a Linux gamer!</title>
      <link>https://trytonvanmeer.dev/posts/2018-02-21-yes-i-am-a-linux-gamer/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://trytonvanmeer.dev/posts/2018-02-21-yes-i-am-a-linux-gamer/</guid>
      <description>Linux is my platform of choice for not only daily computing, but also gaming. And I am happy to say I enjoy it quite a lot.
Steam I might not be able to play all the latest AAA games, but I still have more games to play than I have time. Since I stopped using Windows, I&amp;rsquo;ve also made a point to only buy games that support Linux.
There are currently 416 games in my Steam library.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>